Guide to the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 131 (Seattle, Washington) Records 1888-1960
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 131 Records
1888-1960
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
1228
United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America.$bLocal 131 (Seattle, Wash.)
12 cubic feet
Trade union organization
Trade union organization. Local 131 is a Seattle affiliate of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America.
Open to all users
United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America.Local 131 (Seattle, Wash.)$vArchives; Washington Benevolent Association;; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington)
Personal Papers/Corporate Records;; Labor History; Labor Unions; Washington (State); Seattle
- United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America Local 131 Records, 1888-1960; 1228-001; 12 cubic feet 10 boxes and 2 ledgers
  Correspondence, minutes, financial records, ephemera; 1888-1960.
  Includes Washington Benevolent Association records and minutes of the Portland, Seattle, and Tacoma Building Trades Councils.
  Robert Simon, Secretary, Carpenters Local 131, United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, September 10, 1969
  The records have been divided into two record groups according to creator:
  RECORD GROUP 1: CARPENTERS AND JOINERS OF AMERICA, LOCAL 131
  RECORD GROUP 2: WASHINGTON BENEVOLENT ASSOCIATION.
  RECORD GROUP 1 is divided into seven series and subseries to reflect the records formats and activities of the union. As well, this record group has two subgroups that reflect the creating committee within Carpenters Local 131.
  RECORD SUBGROUP A: CARPENTERS AND JOINERS OF AMERICA. LOCAL 131. WAYS AND MEANS COMMITTEE
  RECORD SUBGROUP B: CARPENTERS AND JOINERS OF AMERICA. LOCAL 131. CARPENTERS UNION BUILDING COMPANY.
  - RECORD GROUP 1: CARPENTERS AND JOINERS OF AMERICA, LOCAL 131, 1888-1960
    - SERIES I: ORGANIZATIONAL FEATURES, 1890-1936 (Box-folder 1/1)
      - Organizational Features, 1890-1936 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - SERIES II: INCOMING LETTERS, 1919-1952 (Box-folder 1/2-1/11)
      - Incoming Letters, 1919-1930 (Box-folder 1/2)
      - Incoming Letters, 1932 (Box-folder 1/3)
      - Incoming Letters and Newsletters - Hardy, J.L.(local 131), Duffy, Frank (National Sec.), 1938-1939 (Box-folder 1/4)
      - Incoming Letters and Newsletters - Hardy, J.L.(local 131), Duffy, Frank (National Sec.), 1940 (Box-folder 1/5)
      - Incoming Letters and Newsletters - Hardy, J.L.(local 131), Duffy, Frank (National Sec.), 1941-1942 (Box-folder 1/6)
      - Incoming Letters and Newsletters - Hardy, J.L.(local 131) and Gen Exec Board, 1943-1948 (Box-folder 1/7)
      - Incoming Letters and Newsletters, 1948 (Box-folder 1/8)
      - Incoming Letters and Newsletters, January 1949-June 1949 (Box-folder 1/9)
      - Incoming Letters and Newsletters, July 1949-December 1949 (Box-folder 1/10)
      - Incoming Letters and Newsletters, 1950-January 1952 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - SERIES III: GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE, 1939-1947 (Box-folder 1/12-1/14)
      - General Correspondence, 1939-1943 (Box-folder 1/12)
      - General Correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 1/13)
      - General Correspondence, 1947-1947 (Box-folder 1/14)
    - SERIES IV: APPLICATIONS, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 1/15)
      - Applications to Retirement Home Lakeland, Florida, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 1/15)
    - SERIES V: TRIAL PROCEEDINGS, 1925 (Box-folder 1/16)
      - Trail Proceeding, August 8, 1925 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - SERIES VI: MINUTES, 1908-1960 (Box-folder 1/17-2/7)
      - SUBSERIES A: MINUTES OF UBCJA LOCAL 131, 1908-1960 (Box-folder 1/17-1/20, 2/4-2/7)
        - Minutes of Local 131, 1908-October 1909 (Box-folder 1/17)
        - Minutes of Local 131, November 1909-May 1913 (Box-folder 1/18)
        - Minutes of Local 131, June 1913-July 2, 1918 (Box-folder 1/19)
        - Minutes of Local 131, July 9, 1918-June 17, 1924 (Box-folder 1/20)
        - Minutes of Local 131, June 1924-March 1933 (Box-folder 2/4)
        - Minutes of Local 131, April 1933-August 1940 (Box-folder 2/5)
        - Minutes of Local 131, June 1945-May 1950 (Box-folder 2/6)
        - Minutes of Local 131, June 1950-December 1960 (Box-folder 2/7)
      - SUBSERIES B: MINUTES OF OTHERS, April 1923-December 1923 (Box-folder 2/1-2/3)
        - Minutes of Portland District Council of Carpenters, April 1923-December 1923 (Box-folder 2/1)
        - Minutes of the Seattle Building Trades Council, August 1928-March 1929 (Box-folder 2/2)
        - Minutes of Tacoma District Council of Carpenters, June 1923-December 1923 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - SERIES VII: FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1888-1954 (Box-folder 3/1-3/13, 4/1-4/2, 4/5-4/10, 4/12, 4/14-4/16, 5/1-6/7, 6/9, 7/1-8/3, Oversize Boxes 9/1-10/1, 10/4-10/5, 11/2-11/5)
      - SUBSERIES A: FINANCIAL RECORDS CONVENTIONAL SIZE, October 1897-1954 (Box-folder 3/1-3/13, 4/1, 4/5-4/10, 4/14-4/16)
        - Sick Benefits, August 1902-April 1910 (Box-folder 3/1)
        - Donations / Locker Rentals, April 1, 1903-December 31, 1916 (Box-folder 3/2)
        - Employee Tax, Payroll Taxes for Local 131 and Wash Benevolent Association, 1943-1951 (Box-folder 3/3)
        - Financial Secretary's Report, 1913-1945 (Box-folder 3/4)
        - Warrants for Contingent Funds, 1908-1911 (Box-folder 3/5)
        - General Fund Check Register, 1922-1925 (Box-folder 3/6)
        - Treasurer's Receipt Book, October 1897-August 1899 (Box-folder 3/7)
        - Treasurer's Cash Book, July 1900-June 1901 (Box-folder 3/8)
        - Treasurer's Cash Book, July 1901-June 1902 (Box-folder 3/9)
        - Treasurer's Cash Book, July 1902-December 1902 (Box-folder 3/10)
        - Fines and Expulsions, 1901-1923 (Box-folder 3/11)
        - Initiation Fees, 1904-1906 (Box-folder 3/12)
        - Application Fees, 1910-1914 (Box-folder 3/13)
        - Rental Records For Hall, 1906-1924 (Box-folder 4/1)
        - Local 131 Check Register, March 1932-August 1936 (Box-folder 4/5)
        - Membership Directory, Undated (Box-folder 4/6)
        - Membership Directory, Undated (Box-folder 4/7)
        - Membership Directory, Undated (Box-folder 4/8)
        - Edison Tech Training Courses, 1950-1950 (Box-folder 4/9)
        - Minutes of the Ways and Means Committee, 1910-1911 (Box-folder 4/10)
        - State Labor Directories, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 4/14)
        - Convention Annual and Reports, 1913-1953 (Box-folder 4/15)
        - Lease Agreements, 1909-1931 (Box-folder 4/16)
      - SUBSERIES B: OVERSIZE FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1888-1942 (Box-folder 5/1-6/7, 6/9, 7/1-8/3, 9/1-10/1, 10/4-10/5, 11/2-11/5)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments, 1888-1890 (Box-folder 5/1)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments, 1888-1899 (Box-folder 5/2)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments, 1891-1898 (Box-folder 5/3)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments [ Ledger #1], 1900 (Box-folder 5/4)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments, 1901 (Box-folder 5/5)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments, May 1902-November 1902 (Box-folder 5/6)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments, 1903 (Box-folder 5/7)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments [Ledger #2], 1900 (Box-folder 6/1)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments, 1908-1909 (Box-folder 6/2)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments, 1914-1922 (Box-folder 6/3)
        - Expense Book, 1901 (Box-folder 6/4)
        - Expense Book, 1902 (Box-folder 6/5)
        - Ledger of Income and Expenses Local 131, May 1903-December 1903 (Box-folder 6/6)
        - Warrant Book, Local 131, 1904-1906 (Box-folder 6/7)
        - General Fund Ledger, March 1938-December 1942 (Box-folder 6/9)
        - Financial Ledger, 1889 (Box-folder 7/1)
        - Financial Ledger, 1888 (Box-folder 7/2)
        - Financial Ledger, 1910-1913 (Box-folder 7/3)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments, 1926-1929 (Box-folder 7/4)
        - Financial Ledger, 1916-1942 (Box-folder 8/1)
        - Financial Ledger, 1905-1916 (Box-folder 8/2)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments, 1902-1902 (Box-folder 8/3)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments, 1916-1918 (Box-folder 9/1)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments, 1904-1907 (Box-folder 9/2)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments, 1921 (Box-folder 10/1)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments, January 2, 1905-December 30, 1905 (Box-folder 10/4)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments, January 1, 1904-December 31, 1904 (Box-folder 10/5)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments, January 23, 1929-June 30, 1931 (Box-folder 11/2)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments, January 1, 1907-August 25, 1908 (Box-folder 11/3)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments, August 26, 1909-July 26, 1910 (Box-folder 11/4)
        - Ledger of Dues and Assessments, September 29, 1920-November 27, 1923 (Box-folder 11/5)
    - RECORD SUBGROUP A: CARPENTERS AND JOINERS OF AMERICA. LOCAL 131. WAYS AND MEANS COMMITTEE, 1910-1911 (Box-folder 4/2)
      - Accounts Payable, 1917-1933 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - RECORD SUBGROUP B: CARPENTERS AND JOINERS OF AMERICA. LOCAL 131. CARPENTERS UNION BUILDING COMPANY., December 1911-December 1922 (Box-folder 4/12)
      - Minutes and Dissolution of Carpenters Union Building Committee, 1901 (Box-folder 4/12)
  - RECORD GROUP 2: WASHINGTON BENEVOLENT ASSOCIATION., 1905-1931 (Box-folder 3/3, 3/14, 4/3, 4/4, 6/7, 4/11, 4/13, 10/2-10/3, 11/1)
    - SERIES I: MINUTES, 1905-1908 (Box-folder 4/11)
      - Minutes of the Washington Benevolent Association, 1905-1908 (Box-folder 4/11)
    - SERIES II: FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1905-1951 (Box-folder 3/3, 3/14, 4/3, 4/4, 6/8, 10/2-10/3, 11/1)
      - Employee Tax, Payroll Taxes for Local 131 and Washington Benevolent Association, 1943-1951 (Box-folder 3/3)
      - Monthly Expenses of General, Contingent and Washington Benevolent Association Funds, 1923-1935 (Box-folder 3/14)
      - Weekly Expenses of General, Contingent and Washington Benevolent Society Funds, December 1911-December 1922 (Box-folder 4/3)